# Jake deVarennes

# Software Engineer

Software Engineer with two years of experience in both Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Led architecture design with a team of four to build Constellation, a geo-distributed load-testing framework. Which can handle up to 10,000 virtual users from all 26 AWS regions at once.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer**

August 2022 - January 2023

Constellation, Co-creator, Houston, TX

- Researched existing products to find most impactful features and explore architectural challenges
- Spearheaded development of the data-aggregation software using Node.js and AWS SDK engineered for a capacity of over 130 requests per second
- Constructed the data visualizer which provides a comprehensive way to ingest data returned from the load generation test from all 26 AWS regions
- Developed CLI command allowing users to accomplish with a single command on Constellation, which would take over 7 API calls to AWS to accomplish
- Managed engineering team that created a buffer system which decreased the data loss to 0% at a rate of over 130 Rps
- Wrote code from scratch which replaces the functionality of 3 open source tools that reduced overall API complexity
- Engineered data ingestion and retrieval system optimized for high read volume and complex analytical queries over large datasets
- Collaborated with a remote team of engineers from the US, New Zealand & Canada, across four time zones involving daily stand ups and pair programming
- Authored Constellation's comprehensive case study defining the problem domain, architectural design decision, and technical challenges faced when developing Constellation

# **Software Engineer**

March 2021 - July 2022

Self-employed, Houston, TX

- Bin of Requests: A Node.js application built using Express, MongoDB, Postman, and PostgreSQL to capture and monitor HTTP requests
- JobQuery: A Node.js job keyword tracking software built with Express, MongoDB, Puppeteer, and React/Redux that processes 900 job listings at once and analyzes the top keywords present in each listing
- Swillreno.com: Architected website using Wordpress and saved the company over \$750.00 and two weeks of development time

## Sales Associate

August 2018 - Feburary 2021

Houston, TX & Reno, NV

- Became number one in contract volume at a medical waste removal startup using email marketing, cold calls, and in person meetings with medical professionals
- Became one of the top 5% of sales people in the region
- Initiated and managed business relationships with key customers

#### CONTACT

- Houston, TX (Open to Remote)
- · +1-530-304-2873
- devarennesjacob@gmail.com
- <u>linkedin.com/in/jakedevar</u>
- \_github.com/jakedevar

## **SKILLS**

## Languages:

- · JavaScript/Node.js
- Ruby
- · Go
- · HTML
- · CSS
- PostgreSQL

#### Tools and Frameworks:

- React
- · Redux.js
- jQuery
- · Express.js
- MongoDB
- Linux
- · Vim and Neovim
- RESTful APIs
- Jest
- Puppeteer
- Bootstrap
- MaterialUI
- Github/Git
- Docker

#### Cloud:

- · AWS
- · Digital Ocean
- Timestream
- EC2
- Fargate
- Lambda
- API Gateway
- · S3
- DynamoDB

## **EDUCATION**

# Launch School

Software Engineering April 2021 – December 2022

# University of Nevada Reno

Bachelor of Arts
Major in General Studies
Minors in Psychology and Anthropology
August 2014 — May 2018